# SANTOSH MANANDHAR

Jorpati, Kathmandu, Nepal·+977-9851144130 santosh.manandhar1@gmail.com·www.linkedin.com/in/smanandhar

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

Process-driven, highly competent IT professional with more than 11 years of experience in administering, managing and maintaining Windows server and computer system. Adept with the level of experience in installing and configuring software, hardware and networks; able to monitor system performance and troubleshoot issues. Possesses an associate certification in Microsoft and Cisco.

# **EXPERIENCE**

RTI INTERNATIONAL – KATHMANDU, NEPAL

IT OFFICER (SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR), FEBRUARY 2018 – PRESENT

IT SPECIALIST, AUGUST 2015 – JANUARY 2018

Hired as IT Specialist for RTI's project in Nepal – Early Grade Reading Program and later promoted to IT Officer (System Administrator) role to be a part of RTI's Global Technology Solutions team to support the global projects, Regional Offices (North America, Latin America, Africa and Asia) and Headquarter of RTI International. Provide configuring, troubleshooting and maintaining Windows infrastructure along with performance-tuning and Tier 2/3 support for approximately 600 Windows servers. **Achievement Highlights:** 

- Project Management: Lead enterprise-wide migration of McAfee VSE to ENS and DNS/DHCP from Server 2008R2/2012 to 2016 that improve security and performance. This task helps to reduce the regular system alerts by 20%.
   Lead to set-up Early Grade Reading Program project office in Kathmandu, Nepal with its 6 regional offices. This project helps me to demonstrate my ability in LAN/WAN configuration, server setup, PABX system and file server backup system.
- **Performance Monitoring:** Configure SolarWinds WPM and NTA monitoring system which actively monitor the status and health of Website, Application, Servers and Juniper Firewalls. Create user-friendly dashboard and report which provide visual information to end-user/supervisor about the current and past status of the systems.
- **AD Management:** Managing 3000+ user accounts and 500+ security groups to provide access to the systems, files share and FTP sites.
- **Security:** Strengthened System security and business-continuity planning as a member of organization's security incident response team.
- **Troubleshooting:** Rectified many issues by instituting best practices in system log analysis, backups, user account/permissions management and file share permission management.

#### **Key responsibilities:**

- Manage virtual server builds and decommissions.
- Monitor systems availability, performance, capacity and security.

- Troubleshoot and resolve problems in response to alerts from monitoring tools or trouble reports from other GTS staff.
- Perform quality control by monitoring contact channels and actively provides feedback when defects are found; log all defects.
- Perform maintenance including installation of patches and upgrades.

# INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR MIGRATION – KATHMANDU AND DAMAK, NEPAL IT ASSISTANT, APRIL 2012 – JULY 2015

### **Achievement Highlights:**

- Reduce Operating System and software installation duration by 60% in desktops and laptops by introducing ghost application like Norton Ghost.
- Configure monitoring of LAN infrastructure which helps to decrease support request by 10%.

## Key responsibilities:

- Onsite and Offsite end-user support.
- Maintenance of ICT equipment.
- Threat prevention.
- Assist in the implementation and management of a centralized data backup system.
- ICT training to end users to ensure productive use of existing and new applications and systems that cut trouble tickets by 18%.

# ELITE NETWORKS PVT. LTD. – KATHMANDU, NEPAL SENIOR SUPPORT EXECUTIVE, DECEMBER 2010 – MARCH 2012

### **Achievement Highlights:**

- Setup radio link connection for various national banks and ATM machines.
- Migrations of in-house server, backup system and MDaemon Email server.
- First time in Nepal Banking sector, implemented ATM monitoring system Wincor
   Preview which monitor the activities and events of ATM machines.
- Design UI for ATM machine and Token Dispenser

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Maintain in-house AD and MDaemon server.
- Monitor network and internet traffic.
- Design, configure, maintain and troubleshoot database for Wincor Preview server.
- Provide technical support to various leading banks and companies.
- IBM server configuration and troubleshooting hardware errors.

# COMMODITIES AND METAL EXCHANGE NEPAL LTD. – KATHMANDU, NEPAL IT OFFICER, NOVEMBER 2007 – JANUARY 2010

#### **Achievement Highlights:**

• Design, implement, maintain and troubleshoot AD service.

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Monitor LAN network.
- Installation, distribution and troubleshoot of in-house trading software.
- Deal with brokers' problem online and offline.
- Maintain daily backup of application database.

# **EDUCATION**

2013 - 2015

MASTERS OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, SIKKIM MANIPAL UNIVERSITY, INDIA

**GRADE B** 

2003 - 2007

**BACHELORS IN INFORMATION MANAGEMENT, TRIBHUVAN UNIVERSITY, NEPAL** 

**CGPA 3.55** 

# **SKILLS**

- Windows System Administration and Repair
- System Security, Backup and Recovery
- Technical Infrastructure (LAN/WAN)
- Hardware and Software upgrade planning
- Technical Support
- Microsoft Office 365
- Desktop/Laptop image ghosting

- Workstation Installation/Configuration
- McAfee ePO Administration
- SolarWinds Monitoring
- VMware ESXi/vSphere
- Active Directory, Group Policies, DNS, DHCP
- Exchange Admin Center
- Service Now

# TECHNICAL CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Certified IT Professional
- Microsoft Certified Solution Associate in Server 2008
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist in Server 2008 Active Directory and Network Infrastructure
- Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician

# **SAFETY TRAINING**

- Basic Security in The Field II
- Advance Security in The Field
- Safe and Secure Approaches in Field Environment
- Protection and Sexual Exploitation and Abuse
- Red Cross Training